Let's look at how vectors are used in the math behind self-driving cars.
我们来看看如何在无人驾驶车所用的数学方法中使用向量
The way we have been representing state is as a list of values which just has a length,
我们表示状态的方式是一个只有一个长度的值的列表
a length of two values, in this case.
本例中 一个长度有两个值
But, a state vector is a column of values whose dimensions are 1 in with an N in height.
但是 状态向量是一列值 其尺寸为 1 高度为 N
And again, in this case, N is 2,
本例中 N 为 2
this makes the state vector a special kind of matrix,
这使状态向量成为一种特殊的矩阵
and we'll see why being a column vector is important, soon.
我们很快会看到为什么列向量很重要
Let's think about our predict state function again.
我们再来考虑一下预测状态函数
It takes in an initial state,
它处于初始状态
and we store the position X and velocity V,
我们存储位置 X 和速度 V
and then we have a couple of lines of code that
然后我们有几行代码
predict the next state based on a constant velocity motion model.
可预测基于恒速运动模型的下一个状态
We calculate the new position,
我们计算新的位置
new X, and put two values,
新的 X 并把两个值
the new position and the velocity,
新的位置和速度
into a new predicted state,
放到一个新的预测状态中
a new list of two values.
一个包括两个新值的列表
But, with a state vector that holds these two values X and B,
但是 通过放置 X 和 B 这两个值的状态向量
we do not need to separate them to perform this calculation.
我们不需要将它们分开来执行此计算
We can actually perform these same calculations in just one multiplication step.
我们实际上可以在一个乘法步骤中进行相同的计算
This step is a matrix multiplication step.
该步骤是矩阵乘法步骤
Matrix multiplication multiplies two grids of numbers,
矩阵乘法将两个数字网格相乘
like this two by two matrix and this two by one state vector,
像这样二乘二矩阵和这个二乘一状态向量
which has a position X and the velocity V,
其位置为 X 速度为 V
and here's how this multiplication works.
接下来 我们看看这个乘法的运算方式
This operation first multiplies the rows in
此运算首先将第一个矩阵中的行乘以
the first matrix by the columns in the second.
第二个矩阵中的列
So, these dimensions, the number of columns in
所以 这些尺寸 第一个矩阵中列的数量
this first matrix and the number of rows in the second have to be the same.
应该和第二个矩阵中行的数量相同
Step by step, this looks like one times X,
一步一步地 这看起来像一乘以X
which is just X, and then, V times dt.
就等于 X 然后 V 乘以 dt
So now, we have the first row in the first Matrix times the column in the second matrix.
那么现在 我们第一个矩阵中的第一行乘以第二个矩阵中的列
The next step is to sum these two values to form a single new value in this new matrix,
下一步是求这两个值的和 从而在这个新矩阵中形成一个新的值
X plus V times dt.
X 加 V 乘以 dt
Then, we do the same with the next row,
然后 对下一行执行同样的运算
and we get 0 times X plus 1 times V,
就是 0 乘以 X 加 1 乘以 V
and summing these values gives us just V. And that's it.
并且将这些值加起来 得到 V 计算完成了
You can see that this creates a new two by
你可以看到 这创造了一个新的二乘以一
one vector with two values in it that may look familiar.
向量 其中有两个值 这看起来似乎很熟悉
In fact, these are just our equations for our constant velocity motion model.
事实上 这些只是我们的恒速运动模型方程
After some change in time,
经过一段时间的改变
X becomes X plus velocity times change in time and V remains constant.
X 变为 X 加上速度乘以时间变化 而 V保持恒定
And so, matrix multiplication let's us create
所以 矩阵乘法可以让我们创建
a new predicted state vector and just one multiplication step.
一个新的预测状态向量和一个乘法步骤
This is such a common way to predict a new state that this two by
这是预测这个新状态的一种常见方式
two Matrix is often called the state transformation matrix.
二乘二矩阵通常被称为状态转换矩阵
Next, we'll test your knowledge about matrix multiplication and
接下来 我们将测试你在矩阵乘法方面的知识
see how we can use this knowledge to improve the predict state function.
看看我们如何使用这些知识来改进预测状态函数